Kelowna School of Resource Management fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Kelowna School of Resource Management fonds
1977 - 1979
F-205
32 cm of textual records 3 architectural drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
GENERAL NOTE Architectural drawings are found in files 30 (2 drawings, file F-205-0-0-0-30) and 31 (1 oversize architectural drawing, F-205-0-0-0-31).
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of these records and production of this finding aid was generously provided by Simon Fraser University's Office of the Vice-President, Academic (October 2005).
Kelowna School of Resource Management
The Kelowna School of Resource Management (KSRM) was a proposed school that Simon Fraser University intended to establish in British Columbia's Interior, offering an undergraduate degree program based on core courses in natural and social sciences and in techniques of resource management and planning. The project was never realized.
Planning began in 1977 as part of SFU's response to the provincial government's Commission on University Programs in Non-Metropolitan Areas (Winegard Commission). The province's degree-program approval authority at that time – the Universities Council of British Columbia (UCBC) – gave approval in principle to SFU's proposal in early 1978. By August the university had appointed John M. Munro (then SFU's Dean of Arts) as the School's first Director, and KSRM began recruiting faculty. The curriculum was designed to provide undergraduate instruction for third- and fourth-year students who had already completed their first two years at community colleges in the province or at other universities. KSRM was to begin operations in September 1979, using facilities on the campus of Okanagan College.
In February 1979 UCBC reversed its earlier decision and rejected the proposal, citing several factors: lack of professional infrastructure at SFU; the employability of graduates; the professional qualifications of graduates; the need for a permanent building; and the financial requirement of $1 million annually. SFU contested each point of the rationale but was unable to overturn the decision. All planning activities were discontinued and the School dissolved. Its Director, Professor Munro, returned to SFU's Department of Economics and Commerce; in June 1979 he became SFU's Vice-President, Academic.
published
Full
Published
The title of the fonds is based on the name of the creating body.
The fonds consists of records made or received by the Director in the course of planning for the establishment and operations of the School. Activities documented include curriculum planning and development; management of the program-approval process; research and site visits to other universities with comparable programs; liaison with other SFU departments, other educational institutions, government and the Kelowna community; recruitment and appointment of School faculty and the hiring of the Director; dissemination of program information to students and media relations; budget and facilities planning; and the activities of SFU's Interior Programming Committee. Record types include correspondence and reports; course proposals, curriculum outlines, drafts and commentaries; brochures, leaflets, program descriptions, reports and studies from other universities; a labour-market survey and related documentation (contract, correspondence, reports); planning committee meeting minutes and supporting papers; position advertisements, lists of faculty candidates, applications, CVs, search committee minutes and working papers; program brochures; budget proposals, projected budgets and notes; space planning reports, studies, and architectural drawings; and press releases, news clippings, and other publicity material.
The fonds consists of 44 files arranged alphabetically following the creator's original order. Because of the small volume of files, the fonds was arranged without series.
Munro, John M.; Okanagan College; Architectural drawings; Textual records
The records formed part of a larger body of files under the control of Academic Planning Services which were appraised and transferred to the Archives in 1994 through a one-time Unscheduled Records Disposal (URD 083-94). This transfer was part of a larger project the Archives undertook to appraise, schedule and dispose of records that had accumulated in the University Records Centre through the 1980s and early 1990s.
All accessions have been processed as of February 2006. No further accruals are expected.
The records were in the custody of the School's director, John Munro. Upon dissolution of the School, the files appear to have moved with Munro to the Office of the Vice-President, Academic when he became VP. Subsequently the records were put in storage with a number of other closed series as a group of "Special Project Files" under the control of Academic Planning Services. In this form they were transferred to the Archives in 1994.
Other records relating to the Kelowna School of Resource Management can be found in the fonds of the Vice-President, Academic (F-200); see series 3-6-8 (Faculties. Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies. Master of Resources Management Program).
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available. The School's original file index is available as file 1 (F-205-0-0-0-1).
- File index, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Pending review
- Advertisements, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Advisory committee, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Appointments committee, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Board of Governors, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Budget, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Budget, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Canadian Institute of Planners, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Correspondence - miscellaneous, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Community colleges, 1979; F-205-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Continuing Studies, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Curriculum correspondence, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Curriculum liaison, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Curriculum Planning Committee, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Curriculum proposals, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Curriculum suggestions, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Department of Indian Affairs, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Director search, vol. 1, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Director search, vol. 2, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Environmental Sciences program, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 205-1)
- Faculty applications, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Faculty appointments, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Federal government liaison, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- G. Gates contract [canvass of employers], 1978; F-205-0-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- [General], 1979; F-205-0-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Humboldt State University, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Huxley College - Western Washington State University, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Interior Program Planning Committee, 1977 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Kelowna degree completion program, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Kelowna facilities, vol. 1, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Kelowna facilities, vol. 2, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-31
- Media contacts - Kelowna, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Newspaper advertisements, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Okanagan College, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Planning Institute of British Columbia, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Press, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Recruiting, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS) approval, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Staff, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- State University of New York (SUNY) - Syracuse campus, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 205-2)
- Universities Council of British Columbia, 1978 - 1979; F-205-0-0-0-41 (Archival box - small 205-3)
- University of Alaska, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-42 (Archival box - small 205-3)
- University of Wisconsin - Green Bay, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-43 (Archival box - small 205-3)
- University of Wisconsin - Stevens Point, 1978; F-205-0-0-0-44 (Archival box - small 205-3)